focalex.com 2008-05-04

# Focalex: Privacy

**Focalex's General Privacy Statement.**

Last Updated on 02/12/2008 

If you have any questions regarding this statement, you should contact our privacy group by email ([privacy@focalex.com](mailto:privacy@focalex.com)) or you can send inquiries via postal mail to: Focalex, Inc., Privacy Group, 450 Sansome Street, Suite 200, San Francisco, CA, 94111. 

This Privacy Policy applies to consumers that have signed up via Focalex.com. Focalex may edit this privacy policy from time to time. When we make any substantial changes of users' Personally Identifiable Information, we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on our privacy policy and our home page, [www.focalex.com](http://www.focalex.com/) and we will provide an opportunity for you to opt-out of any further use of your Personally Identifiable Information. 

Focalex created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site. To ensure that all of our users are completely opt-in, we have a double opt-in confirmation mechanism. We also make it easy for our subscribers to unsubscribe whenever they want without hassle. Focalex focuses on getting permission from subscribers to send information, NOT spam. 

## Information Collection and Use

_Registration_

Our site's registration forms ask for users to provide us their email address and zip code. In addition, subscribers may optionally provide additional demographic and psychographic information in the sign up form, the sign up process, or later through contests, surveys, and other web activities. This information includes, but is not limited to, mailing address, industry, occupation, age, gender, or phone number. We collect this information in an effort to better target user interests. Completing the forms is completely voluntary and no user is obligated to provide this information to Focalex. 

Focalex offers various contests, promotions, and surveys to surfers, which may ask for further demographic information. This information is for use by Focalex for tracking and targeting purposes and is stored in our database. Mailing addresses, phone numbers, fax numbers, and demographics may be provided to third parties for advertising purposes as required in the contest rules. 

In accordance with COPPA regulations, Focalex, Inc. does not allow individuals aged 13 or younger to participate in contests and promotions on pages where Focalex asks for age. Data is not collected from individuals specifying an age of 13 or less. Focalex in some cases employs a drop down box that will only collect data from those citing a year that states their age to be over 13. 

_Refer a Friend_

You may refer a friend to our offers, by using the refer-a-friend service. If you do so, we will ask for your friend's name and email address. We will send your friend a one-time email message inviting him or her to visit the site. Focalex uses this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email message. 

_Publishers_

We additionally allow publishers to join our affiliate program. The signup form for this program requires similar information, in addition to sensitive information such as social security number or tax ID. When you enter your social security number on our application form, we encrypt it using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

Publishers have the opportunity to refer another publisher to our affiliate program. If you do so, like Refer-a-Friend, we will ask for the publisher's name and email address. We will send the publisher a one-time email message inviting him or her to visit the site. Focalex does not store this information in its database, and uses it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email message. 

_Uses Of Information_

Focalex is a direct marketer that delivers targeted messages to the email addresses of specific community members. Subscribers of the Focalex community have requested that they receive information. If a user subscribes to our mailings, we ask for information to efficiently target a particular interest and ultimately offer the subscriber, with quality and efficiency, exactly what he/she has opted to receive. 

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

_Aggregate Information_

We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our partners and advertisers. This information does not identify individual users. We do not link aggregate data with personally identifiable information. 

_Personally Identifiable Information_

Focalex shares email addresses and other demographic information with third parties for mail delivery on behalf of Focalex. In these cases, Focalex only uses trusted partners, and has strong non-disclosure agreements in place to prevent any privacy concerns. Focalex shares data with trusted third parties to prevent you, the subscriber, from receiving duplicate offers and to provide the best possible service for the subscriber. Focalex will not disseminate personally identifiable information, except that we use the personal information that you supply to us with other third party businesses to bring selected opportunities to you via direct mail, email and telemarketing. These businesses include providers of direct marketing services and applications, including lookup and reference, data enhancement, suppression and validation and email marketing. 

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and / or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our web site. 

## Choice / Opt-Out

Users will be given the opportunity to opt out of any future mailings at any time by sending an email to the unsubscribe address in most messages. Users wishing to unsubscribe can also send a message to [help@focalex.com](mailto:%20help@focalex.com). 

Focalex handles unsubscribe requests at [help@focalex.com](mailto:help@focalex.com). These requests are processed within a week of the request. Be aware that Focalex also includes both an unsubscribe address and a purge address in the header of most mailings. 

## Use Of Cookies

Focalex uses cookies for a variety of purposes. Cookies are a piece of data stored in the browser's memory, and may or may not be written to the surfer's hard drive when the browser is closed. This allows customization of what is displayed to the surfer across sessions, enables tracking of user actions, and user profiling. Information stored in cookies may be added to Focalex's databases, or used as a means to identify a user. While a user can use Focalex sites without cookies enabled, displays will not be customized, and in some cases, the site may not work at all. Turning off cookies also limits the ability, or in some cases precludes the ability, to participate in various Focalex contests and giveaways. Some of the advertisers who use our site (both on the web and in e-mail messages) may use cookies on their site. This is something over which Focalex has no control. See "Third Party Advertisers". 

## Web Beacons / Web Bugs

We employ image loading tracking (a.k.a. Web Beacons / Web Bugs) that help us better manage offers provided on our site by letting us know what offers are effective, as well as to track activity via email. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, to track the online movements of Web users. We additionally use graphics that are not clear gifs for a similar purpose. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, these images are embedded on web pages. In the case of clear gifs, they are invisible and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by image loading tracking to our customers' personally identifiable information, but not to information such as credit card, financial information, or social security numbers. 

This information is used to track the effectiveness of campaigns, as well as the effectiveness or particular offers. 

## Third Party Advertisers

The web pages at [ www.focalex.com](http://www.focalex.com/) and some of the email sent by Focalex contain links to external sites beyond our control. Focalex cannot represent or guarantee that these third parties' privacy statements conform to our privacy policies. Any site linked to the Focalex site may have a Privacy Statement that differs from our own. Please review the privacy statement of any site linked from Focalex. 

From time to time Focalex may offer the opportunity to sign up to third party offers through the signup process. When this is the case, the offerings will be clearly marked as signups for that third party. Signing up for such offerings is completely voluntary and not required for any Focalex services. If the user does not wish to sign up for those offers, the user should simply not submit to them. As such, information submitted on those offerings may be submitted to the third party. Please refer to the third party's privacy policies for further information. For more information on third party ad servers, please refer to the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

Additionally, Focalex may provide individual or summarized information to reputable third parties when, for whatever reason, Focalex is unable to deliver to specific advertisers though our current delivery system. 

## Access To Personally Identifiable Information

Updates to your list preferences can be made by using the manage preferences link in most email messages. If you would like to correct, update, delete, or deactivate other profile information, you can do so by contacting customer support at [help@focalex.com](mailto:help@focalex.com), or by sending a postal mail message to Focalex, Inc., 450 Sansome Street, Suite 200, San Francisco, CA 94111 

## Security

This site has security measures in place to ensure against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control. Focalex protects the integrity and security of its data by following industry-standard procedures and guidelines. Only key executives and members of the development team at Focalex possess the passwords required to access files requiring security clearances. All Focalex employees are made aware of corporate security policies upon hire, change of position or change of policy. 

Focalex, Inc. does have a security module in place. The module encrypts the Social Security Number and/or Tax ID Number, which is required upon registration to the Focalex Affiliate Program. The encryption and security measures taken to protect this information will protect you, the user, from any harmful external activity, such as computer hackers. The information is only available to the accountant of Focalex, Inc. and those members of the development team who possess passwords to secure areas of the Focalex Network. 

## Indemnity

The subscriber agrees to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Focalex and its directors, officers, agents, and employees for any and all losses, costs, liabilities or expenses (including, without limitation, reasonable attorneys' and expert witnesses' fees) incurred or arising from (a) any breach of Subscriber's Covenants, (b) any user-generated content or (c) any claims arising from the sale or license of goods or services promoted or made available through Focalex. Focalex's indemnity rights shall not be limited or offset by any contributory negligence by Focalex. Focalex may participate in the defense at its expense. 

Any additional information offered or any additional services requested by you, the user, outside of the Focalex, Inc. domain will be subject to the Privacy Statement within that particular site. Focalex is not responsible for actions by the user outside of the focalex.com web site. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding the policies of this site or your dealings with this site, please send an email message to: [privacy@focalex.com](mailto:privacy@focalex.com), or send postal mail to Privacy Group, Focalex Inc., 450 Sansome Street, Suite 200, San Francisco, CA 94111.
